

SWAPNIL SHIRISH SATHE Email:swapnilsathe47@yahoo.in swapnilsathe1983@gmail.com / Mobile: +91-9049429372/7020494607

Skype ID: swapnil.sathe@live.com

Summary

An IT Professional with experience in Active Directory, Windows Administration and networking. Maintain Microsoft Active Directory Environments. Utilize Active Directory DNS/DHCP, security and policy design and technology support Domain Services, Users and Computers. Provide end users with hardware and software support on time within the support SLA. Built installed ad configured servers managed them remotely for software upgrades and patches.

Career Objective

To utilize my technical and management skills for achieving the target and delivering the best performance in the organization. I would like to implement my innovative ideas, skills and creativity for accomplishing the projects.

Educational Qualifications

- **B.com** from EIILM University with 52.5% Marks.
- **H.S.C** from AHMEDNAGAR collage with 48.5% Marks.

Technical Trainings

- MCSE (Windows Server 2003) from IT Admin Pvt Ltd, NETX, India
- MCITP (Windows Server 2008,288R2) from IT Admin Pvt Ltd NETX

Certifications (MCP ID: (7301528)

- Microsoft Certified Professional
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist
- Windows Server 2003, Active Directory Configuring (070-290)
- Windows 7, Configuring (070-270)
- Dell certification course no ES404CL101023

Professional Experience

Innovative Tech Hub Pvt Ltd 9-August 2023 TO Till date

IT Operations Manager responsibilities include monitoring network infrastructure and resolving system issues. You need to have experience with IT performance management, network administration and system security. If you're also familiar with data protection regulations and able to juggle multiple projects, we'd like to meet you.

Ultimately, you'll ensure our IT systems are secure, consistent and reliable.

Responsibilities

- Maintain and optimize local company networks and servers
- Be responsible for device and password management
- Oversee data backup and system security operations (e.g. user authorization, firewalls)
- Manage installations, upgrades and configurations of hardware and software
- Assess system performance and recommend improvements
- Resolve issues escalated by technicians and engineers
- Ensure data is handled, transferred or processed according to legal and company guidelines
- Provide support and guidance to stakeholders via help desk
- Manage contracts with vendors (e.g. development platforms, telecommunication companies, password managers) and software licenses
- Develop IT policies and practices
- Configure & Troubleshooting DFS
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems
- Working Share drive Access Active directory on server 2012
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting.
- configure Terminal server
- Attending day to day call from end users and supporting their issues.
- Windows patch management and software update.
- Installing and troubleshooting Windows OS,
- Trouble shooting Servers
- Installing, upgrading & troubleshooting Device Drivers, Operating System, Application Software (MS Office & Office 365
- Responsible to Manage IT infra inventory and manage records.
- Provide share drive Access to users
- Working Application Like Baan Koufax Barware ETC.
- Coordinate with Next Level Support Teams for escalated Issues and ensure resolution at the earliest.
- Work on tickets As monitoring the tickets Escalation

IMPACT INFOTECH PVT.LTD 6-JUNE 2022 31-12-2022

- Managing Active Directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting
- Managing the DNS server
- Configuration & management of Enterprise Wi-Fi System
- Manage of Windows server 2003 to 2008 2012 2019
- Configure NAP Access Protection
- Configure & Troubleshooting DFS
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems
- Working Share drive Access Active directory on server 2012
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting.
- configure Terminal server
- Attending day to day call from end users and supporting their issues.
- Windows patch management and software update.
- Installing and troubleshooting Windows OS,
- Trouble shooting Servers
- Installing, upgrading & troubleshooting Device Drivers, Operating System, Application Software (MS Office & Office 365
- Provide Remote support on call or using remote Desktop/Skype.
- Co-ordinate with vendors for support for hardware/software upgrade.
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems.
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Configure DFS & Replication
- Keeping the network up and running.
 Adding/deleting/creating/modifying user account
- Creating ADC's wherever required
- Monitoring AD replication on daily basis
- Clean-up of old ADC server's records from AD database
- Modifying users attributes like contact details, Email ID etc. as to keep the AD user data updated
- Performing clean-up of stale AD objects on daily/weekly basis
- Adding system into domain by following Client compliance & processes
- Managing file server & other users account security access through AD group management
- Assigning Citrix access resources to end users
- Creating DNS entries for servers & application URL's as per requirement & by following Client approval process
- Active directory group policy creation & management
- End user system domain addition
- Server(Physical/Virtual) Management
- Daily monitoring of Servers for the Server connection and troubleshooting, resolving server operational problems.
- Installation of new servers as per client requirement
- Managing Hyper V server
- Upgrading server resources wherever required as per current load & customer requirement
- Server disk addition/removal/extent / resize.
- Hardware issues are monitoring. Register complaints & follow-up with respective vendors

- Installation and support for Operating Systems running on Server e.g. Windows and other System Software, as and when required.
- Hardening of server accesses as to keep server secure from internal/external attacks
- Downloading & installation of various upgrades, bug fixes, updates, Operating System patches, Security patches of and other System Software's
- Monitoring of resources like CPU utilization, memory utilization, disk space usage, average load, etc. Setting thresholds using conesiq server monitoring tool.
- Performing disk clean-up wherever required & highlighting the same to concern application authority
- Changing the system configuration parameters and re-organization the Disk space, RAM etc. wherever required
- Escalating unresolved problems to OEM/Service Provider for ensuring resolution.
- Support for installation & smooth running of various Services running on Servers.
- Reporting Hardware warning / issues to client & resolving in coordination with vendors
- Provide support for Storage Management, such as Configuring disk arrays, RAID etc.
- VPN server user creation & access management
- Troubleshooting and Resolving VPN related Issues.
- Ensure all critical services are running on the servers.
- Ensure that all Servers are kept virus free with coordination of Antivirus Admin & AV OEM.
- Support for configuring new solution/installation on old devices
- Responsible for taking inventory of servers & keeping this records up to date
- Periodic system state backup of critical Infrastructure servers.
- Performing backup of all location DHCP & for few File servers
- Coordinating with different Vendors for different projects & fulfilling their requirements by following Client process

MIPL SOLUCTION PVT LTD (2 April 2019) - (30 SEP 2021)

IT Administrator

- Managing Audio/Video Conference with Cisco WebEx Configure network print
- Configure outlook 2013,2016 working excel & office 365
- Handle Day to Day IT related Issue in branch office and remote location
- Configuration of Print devices (network and local) on Desktops.
- Work on data backup process.
- Experience in installing Patches, Upgrades and Licensed Product & System Software
- Responsible for primary investigation with network issue with network switches, router.
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting
- Managing the DNS server
- Configuration & management of Enterprise Wi-Fi System
- Manage of Windows server 2003 to 2008 2012 2019
- Configure NAP Access Protection
- Configure & Troubleshooting DFS
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems
- Working Share drive Access Active directory on server 2012
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting.

- configure Terminal server
- Attending day to day call from end users and supporting their issues.
- Windows patch management and software update.
- · Installing and troubleshooting Windows OS,
- Trouble shooting Servers
- Creating ADC's wherever required
- Monitoring AD replication on daily basis
- Clean-up of old ADC server's records from AD database
- Modifying users attributes like contact details, Email ID etc. as to keep the AD user data updated
- Managing Hyper V server
- Upgrading server resources wherever required as per current load & customer requirement
- Server disk addition/removal/extent / resize.
- Hardware issues are monitoring. Register complaints & follow-up with respective vendors
- Installation and support for Operating Systems running on Server e.g. Windows and other System Software, as and when required.
- Hardening of server accesses as to keep server secure from internal/external attacks
- Downloading & installation of various upgrades, bug fixes, updates, Operating System patches, Security patches of and other System Software's
- Monitoring of resources like CPU utilization, memory utilization, disk space usage, average load, etc. Setting thresholds using conseil server monitoring tool.
- Performing clean-up of stale AD objects on daily/weekly basis
- Adding system into domain by following Client compliance & processes
- Managing file server & other users account security access through AD group management
- Assigning Citrix access resources to end users
- Creating DNS entries for servers & application URL's as per requirement & by following Client approval process
- Active directory group policy creation & management
- End user system domain addition
- Server(Physical/Virtual) Management
- Configure and Troubleshoots Issues with Avaya IP phones.
- Coordinate Network Team for network related major issue till Fix.
- Responsible to Manage IT infra inventory and manage records.
- Provide share drive Access to users
- Working Application Like Baan Koufax Barware ETC.
- Coordinate with Next Level Support Teams for escalated Issues and ensure resolution at the earliest.
- Work on tickets which are Assign IT support Issues and resolve in ticketing tool.
- Provide Remote support on call or using remote desktop/Skype.
- Co-ordinate with vendors for support for hardware/software upgrade.
- PATCHING Troubleshooting & configuration
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems.
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting
- Managing the DNS server
- Configure DFS &Replication
- · Maintenance of Domain and clients.
- Working Application Like Baan Koufax Basware

- Monitoring the Data cabling works.
- Configuration & management of Enterprise Wi-Fi System
- Manage of Windows server 2003 to 2008.2008 R2
- Configure NAP Access Protection
- Configure & Troubleshooting DFS
- Trouble shooting computers and laptops.
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems
- Working Share drive Access Active directory on server 2012
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting.
- Level 2 ticket handling
- Attending day to day call from end users and supporting their issues.
- Configuring, assembling Personal Computers & Responsible for troubleshooting Hardware issues.
- Installing and troubleshooting Windows OS,
- Trouble shooting Servers
- · Installation and maintenance of printers.
- Installing, upgrading & troubleshooting Device Drivers, Operating System, Application Software's (MS Office & Office 365)

CMS IT Services PVT LTD (14 March 2017) - (4 February 2019)

IT Administrator (Team Lead)

- Manage entire purchase of inventory related to hardware, software and other IT supplies.
- Daily Backup & File Back up. Monthly Backup
- Inform Management about industry innovations and recommend relevant upgrades.
- · Monitoring the Data cabling works.
- Configuration & management of Enterprise Wi-Fi System
- Manage of Windows server 2003 to 2008.2008 R2
- Configure NAP Access Protection
- Configure & Troubleshooting DFS
- Trouble shooting computers and laptops.
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems.
- · Maintenance of Domain and clients.
- LAN implementation and trouble shooting.
- Installation and Maintenance of Windows 2008 server, XP, Win7, Win8.1 and MS -Office tools.
- Perform workstations along with existing and operational printer
- Installing Active directory and ensured the security by implementing Group policy
- Network Video Recorder Configuration and maintenance.
 Installation DNS DHCP Active directory & FSMO Roles
- Troubleshooting small business server
- Installation and Maintenance of all necessary Software.
- VMware Workstation Installation and configure Virtual Machine
- Maintaining services server workstation & printers
- Providing Remote support to the user
- Providing Remote support like VNC viewer team viewer
- Managing Audio/Video Conference with Cisco WebEx Configure network print

- Taking care of Sla Parameter, Arrange Shift Rosters, Weekly Meeting & Discussion about Sla Count.
- Handle Day to Day IT related Issue in branch office and remote location
- Configuration of Print devices (network and local) on Desktops.
- Work on data backup process at Tivoli Storage Manager Operations Centre.
- Experience in installing Patches, Upgrades and Licensed Product & System Software
- Responsible for primary investigation with network issue with network switches, router.
- Configure and Troubleshoots Issues with Avaya IP phones.
- Coordinate Network Team for network related major issue till Fix.
- Troubleshooting any reported problems.
- System performance tuning.
- · Keeping the network up and running.
- Monitoring checks of systems/software.
- · Performing backups of data.
- Applying operating system updates, and configuration changes.
- Installing and configuring new hardware/software.
- Adding/deleting/creating/modifying user account information, rese Ting, Passwords in Active directory.
- Responsibility for documenting the configuration of the system.
- · Keeping the network up and running.

VDA INFOSOLUTIONS (6-OCTOBER 2015) -(7 NOVEMBER 2016)

IT Administrator

- Manage entire purchase of inventory related to hardware, software and other IT supplies.
- Inform Management about industry innovations and recommend relevant upgrades.
- Monitoring the Data cabling works.
- Configuration & management of Enterprise Wi-Fi System
- Manage of Windows server 2003 to 2008.
- Trouble shooting computers and laptops.
- Patching Troubleshooting & configuration
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems.
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting
- Managing the DNS server
- Configure DFS & Replication
- · Maintenance of Domain and clients.
- LAN implementation and trouble shooting.
- Installation and Maintenance of Windows 2008R2 server, XP, Win7, Win8.1 and MS -Office tools.
- Perform workstations along with existing and operational printer
- Installing Active directory and ensured the security by implementing Group policy
- Network Video Recorder Configuration and maintenance.
- Installation and Maintenance of all necessary Software.
- VMware Workstation Installation and configure Virtual Machine
- Providing Remote support to the user
- Troubleshooting maintaining server
- Handling various VPN AT&T
- Providing Remote support like Lync VNC viewer team viewer

- Managing Audio/Video Conference with Cisco WebEx Configure network printer.
- Provide Remote support on call or using remote desktop/Skype.
- Co-ordinate with vendors for support for hardware/software upgrade.
- Installing OS, configuring printers and modems.
- Managing Active directory user & computers
- Installation DHCP server create a scope super scope Reservation & Troubleshooting
- Managing the DNS server
- Configure DFS & Replication
- Keeping the network up and running.
- Adding/deleting/creating/modifying user account information, rese Ting, Passwords in Active directory.
- Responsibility for documenting the configuration of the system.
- Handle Day to Day IT related Issue in branch office and remote location
- Configuration of Print devices (network and local) on Desktops.
- Work on data backup process at Tivoli Storage Manager Operations Centre.
- Experience in installing Patches, Upgrades and Licensed Product & System Software

Hardware, Networking & Administration Skills

Windows Server

- Migration of Windows servers.
- Installation and configuration of ADDS.
- Installation and configuration of Additional DC and RODC.
- Creating and managing Active Directory Objects.
- Implementing and managing Child Domain.
- Implementing and resolving Group Policy.
- Installing and configuring DNS, DHCP and other related services.
- Active Directory Backup and restore.
- FSMO role from one DC to another DC.
- Installation and configuration of VPN on Windows Server.
- · Creating and managing RAID on Windows Server
- Configuration DFS
- Level 2 ticket handling
- Terminal Server as well remote desktop Configuration
- Attending day to day call from end users and supporting their issues.
- Windows patch management and software update.
- Configuring, assembling Personal Computers & Responsible for troubleshooting Hardware issues.
- Installing and troubleshooting Windows OS
- Trouble shooting Server Computers.
- Installation and maintenance of printers.
- Installation, configuration and optimization of, XP, Win7, Win8 & Windows10 Windows 11
- Installing, upgrading &troubleshooting Device Drivers, Operating System, Application Soft wares (MS Office,) & Office 365

• Windows Server 2003, 2008, 2008R2 2012 R2 2019 installation and maintenance.

Hyper-V Virtualization

- Installation and configuration of Hyper-V.
- Creating and configuring new VM on Hyper-V Server.
- Creating VHD & VNet in Hyper V

Personal Details

Date of Birth 28-MARCH-1983.

• Gender Male.

• Contact No 9049429372,_7020494607

Marital Status Married

• Nationality Indian

• **Religion** Christian

• Language Known English, HINDI, MARATH

١

Hobbies Playing Cricket, & Traveling Hill Station.

• Passport details

Declaration:

I hereby do solemnly affirm that the details furnished here are true to the best of my knowledge and belief, for any discrepancies found, I shall be fully responsible.